Noviyana

DKI Jakarta, Indonesia / lingnoviyana123@gmail.com / +6282176319252

Summary

An Informatics Engineering student who loves to design and make websites according to user needs. Being a leader in a community called Google Developer Student Clubs (GDSC) taught me how to do teamwork and management skills, as well as sharing knowledge and experience with each other. Experienced making UI/UX design for various projects and developing websites using React.js and Express.js.

Experience

Binar Academy

Full Stack Developer

August 2022 - Present

- Here I joined Studi Independen Program run by Kampus Merdeka and learned about full stack web development, both from the
 frontend side using React.js and the backend side using Express.js.
- For the final project, I took part as a frontend developer and responsible for creating UI design as well as making the frontend side of airline ticket booking web using React.js and Redux.

UI Ling

Freelance UI/UX Designer

December 2020 - June 2022

Here I provide UI/UX design services based on client needs and did some design exploration too. Some design that I've been made include:

- Edufun: Kid Learning Game App
- Student Admission Website Redesign for SMK Tunas Pembangunan
- Travelio: Tour Travel Agency Website
- Peticare: Pet Care Service Website
- Sehatin: App to promote healthy lifestyle

Skilvul

UI/UX Designer

August 2021 – December 2021

Here I'm responsible for redesigning Campaign App by adding Gamification Feature, starting from research and ideation process, creating wireframe, high fidelity design, and do some usability testing.

IndoGold

Front End Web Developer

February 2019 - August 2019

I'm responsible to redesign and build website for PT. IndoGold Company using Bootstrap framework and Javascript to attract user's attention, fulfill user needs, and increase sales of gold. Here we gained user visit up to 60% from the previous one.

Education

Informatics Engineering

Esa Unggul University, DKI Jakarta, Indonesia

GPA in 4th semester: 4.00 out of 4.00

2020 - now

Computer Network Engineering

SMK N 1 Parittiga, Bangka Belitung, Indonesia 2017-2020

Competition & Certification

Web Technologies Student Competency Competition (LKS)

1st placement in Bangka Belitung Province

Dinas Pendidikan Pemuda dan Olahraga - November 2018

Responsible for creating a Micro, Small, and Medium Enterprises (MSME) website using Codelgniter and Bootstrap Framework, as well as designing the page. Continue to the national competition, I was responsible to create a Tic-Tac Toe game using JavaScript, a website using WordPress, and project management website using Vue and Laravel framework.

Junior Web Programmer Certificate of Competence

ICT Professional Certification Institution

July 2019

Here I took a certification for Junior Web Programmer by LSP TIK Indonesia. There's a test and interview about my experience in web development area and tech stack I used for.

Organizational Experience

Google Developer Student Clubs Lead

September 2022 - present

Here I'm responsible for managing, planning, and ensuring the growth of the community, both for core team, members, as well as for the society to create impact through technology. We create some events that aim to teach people about technology, such as webinars, study jams, and mentoring sessions.

XL Future Leaders Awardee

September 2021 - present

Selected with 189 other students from 41.174 applicants across Indonesia with only 0,46% acceptance rate. Here I learn about leadership development: effective communication, entrepreneurship and innovation, also managing changes through workshops and several social projects, such as #BersamaSebarKebaikan Campaign supported by XL Axiata.

Skills

- Design: Figma, Whimsical, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD.
- Frontend Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript, React.Js, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS.
- Backend Development: Node.Js, Express.Js, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgresSQL.

Languages

Indonesian, English

Contact Informations

- Whatsapp/Phone: +6282176319252
- Email: lingnoviyana123@gmail.com
- Instagram: @novyna__ @ui.ling @idiotcoding__
- Website: https://noviyana12.github.io/
- Github: https://github.com/noviyana12
- Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/noviyana-ling12/